### **Damir Yodgorov**

dydamirbey@gmail.com (416) 720 0381 Toronto, ON View My Portfolio www.linkedin.com/in/damiryodgorov

### **PROFILE**

Full Stack Developer with 3+ years of hands-on experience designing, developing, and implementing applications and solutions using a range of technologies and programming languages. Designed and developed web applications across multiple platforms, third-party integrations, and databases.

Databases: Oracle, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB

**Programming Languages**: C, C++, C#, JavaScript, PHP,

XML

**Operating Systems: Windows** 

**Web Development:** HTML5, CSS3, CSS Grid, Flexbox, Bootstrap 5, React + React Hooks, Redux, jQuery, JSON, Node.js, Express.js, NPM, RESTful API Design, SQL

**Tools**: MS Office, Dev C++, Visual Studio, Sublime Text, Atom, MS Visual Code, GitHub, SVN, Eclipse, Heroku, Netlify

### **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATES**

Computer Programmer Diploma (CPD)2017 - 2019Seneca College, York CampusToronto, ON

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Engineering
Eastern Mediterranean University

2013 - 2016
North Cyprus

**SMILE Certificate of Achievement**Seneca College, York Campus

Toronto, ON

ABET Certificate

Accreditation Board for Engineering and Technology

North Cyprus

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Full Stack Software Developer Fortress Technology Inc

September 2021 - Present Toronto, ON

- Maintain and support multiple projects
- Introduce and develop new features to products
- Participate in debugging and bug fixes

# Implementation Specialist/Computer Programmer VelocityEHS

May 2019 - September 2021 Toronto, ON

- Create and configure applications for implementing SaaS solutions for clients
- Create dashboards, reports, notifications, web parts/widgets and components for the application using front-end (CSS, JS and JQUERY) and back-end (SQL, C#) tools
- Improve internal processes by creating standard reports, PDFs, imports, sites, and tools
- Investigate, diagnose, and resolve system and programming issues

## **Damir Yodgorov**

dydamirbey@gmail.com (416) 720 0381 Toronto, ON <u>View My Portfolio</u> www.linkedin.com/in/damiryodgorov

# Software Developer CJSC MDO- IMON INTERNATIONAL

May 2016 - July 2017 Khujand, Tajikistan

- With a team of 6 developers created ticket management system "Help Desk"
- Optimized company's website www.imon.tj.
- Analyzed client services data using SQL

### **PROJECTS**

### **Smart Brain Web Application**

- Experience Created a complex image recognition app using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap 5, JavaScript, React + React Hooks, Node.js, Express.js, NPM, RESTful API Design, SQL and PostgreSQL. As well as used third-party AI (Artificial Intelligence) Clarifai API to detect the face on the picture.
- Application Summary The application allows users to register, sign in and upload any image and detect face if exists. In addition, users can update their information on the profile page including passwords. Furthermore, there is an administrator who has complete control of the application. The administrator can monitor the activities as well as delete, create, and update information about every user in the system.

### **Expense Tracker**

- **Experience** Using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and React + React Hooks created an expense tracker web application where users can manage their expenses.
- Application Summary Using the application, user can add expenses that have name and cost, remove expenses, view the remaining budget, view how much they have spent, edit a budget, and search expenses. The application helps to have control over every expense and maintain healthy financial status.

### **Immigration Guideline**

- **Experience** Using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQUERY, Bootstrap, SQL, and PHP created a web application that acts as a guideline for immigrants in the Russian Federation.
- **Application Summary** The app was similar to the government website where users were able to stay updated with news, ask a question from an Immigration Officer, and get information regarding their immigration process.

### **VOLUNTEERING**

SMILE Mentor Seneca College, York Campus Sept 2018 - April 2019 Toronto, ON

- Taught students the fundamental logic of programming
- Helped students learn to program in easy and fun way
- Helped students deal with issues in Academic areas
- Prepared and submitted monthly report about each student